<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects | Toan Vo</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Projects</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Manager</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/workspace-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/workspace-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, I worked with a team to develop Workspace Manager, a tool designed to streamline workflow by allowing users to create and manage custom workspaces. The goal of the application was to help users quickly launch all the necessary applications, files, and tools for specific tasks with just one click. This project was built using JavaScript and MongoDB as the backend database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The application supports multiple users, each with the ability to create personalized workspaces. With password-encrypted accounts, it ensures secure access and keeps your workspace configurations private. Users can easily add and store multiple file paths and applications within each workspace, so everything you need for a particular task is just a single action away.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-password-encryption&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Password&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /projects/workspace-manager/password_hu15995198970756600996.webp 400w,
               /projects/workspace-manager/password_hu14194605477834363925.webp 760w,
               /projects/workspace-manager/password_hu9877865158993187127.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/workspace-manager/password_hu15995198970756600996.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;286&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Password encryption
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of attendance on SAT scores</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/sat-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/sat-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As part of a team of four, we set out to analyze the relationship between school attendance and SAT scores in New York high schools using data from 2010. Our primary objective was to explore how student attendance impacted SAT performance, while also examining differences between SAT reading and writing scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We worked with two main datasets: the SAT College Board 2010 results, which included mean scores for reading, writing, and math, and a dataset from the NYC Department of Education, detailing daily attendance by school. After pre-processing and merging the data, we used R to run a regression analysis to investigate the correlation between mean SAT scores and average school attendance. Additionally, we conducted hypothesis testing to determine if there was a significant difference between SAT reading and writing scores.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our findings are as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Impact of Attendance on SAT Scores: Our regression model revealed a positive relationship between school attendance and total SAT scores (sum of reading, writing, and math). The linear regression model predicted that a school with 100% attendance would have an average total SAT score of 1395.292. However, the residual plot suggested that the relationship may be non-linear, indicating that a quadratic model could better represent the data.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;SAT analysis&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /projects/sat-analysis/image_hu8007387510409428976.webp 400w,
               /projects/sat-analysis/image_hu16887807423629504061.webp 760w,
               /projects/sat-analysis/image_hu5486022362280592373.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/sat-analysis/image_hu8007387510409428976.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;543&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difference Between SAT Reading and Writing Scores: Through hypothesis testing, we found a significant difference between mean SAT reading and writing scores (p-value &amp;lt; 2.2e-16). The mean difference was about 6.54 points, with reading scores typically higher than writing scores. This suggests that improving reading scores does not necessarily result in equivalent gains in writing scores.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;SAT analysis&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /projects/sat-analysis/image2_hu7765877957456203830.webp 400w,
               /projects/sat-analysis/image2_hu14633620622956661929.webp 760w,
               /projects/sat-analysis/image2_hu16173688565652375430.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/sat-analysis/image2_hu7765877957456203830.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;543&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our analysis supported the idea that increased attendance has a positive impact on SAT performance, though further research is needed to explore the non-linear relationship indicated by the residuals. This project honed my skills in R programming, regression analysis, and hypothesis testing, while providing an opportunity to collaborate on meaningful educational research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out our report 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highway crossing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/highway-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/highway-crossing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this collaborative project, I worked with a team of three to design and develop a 3D car highway crossing game using C# and OpenGL. The primary objective of the game was to guide a car through multiple lanes of fast-moving highway traffic without crashing into obstacles. The game offered players a challenging and engaging experience with progressively more difficult levels as they navigated through increasingly congested highways and obstacle speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;video controls&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;demo.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My key responsibilities included rendering 3D objects and textures using OpenGL, enhancing the overall appearance of the game world. We utilized OpenGL to model cars, roads, and other environmental elements, focusing on clear and functional visuals rather than realistic graphics. Additionally, I implemented audio effects to provide a more immersive experience for players, with sounds for engine revs and collisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Texture&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /projects/highway-crossing/TEXTURE_hu925617358589037926.webp 400w,
               /projects/highway-crossing/TEXTURE_hu8842902378955336288.webp 760w,
               /projects/highway-crossing/TEXTURE_hu12546112924245178659.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/highway-crossing/TEXTURE_hu925617358589037926.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;760&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout development, we collaborated closely, solving challenges such as optimizing object collisions, creating responsive controls, and synchronizing audio with gameplay. The project not only deepened my understanding of OpenGL and C#, but also honed my skills in teamwork, problem-solving, and game mechanics development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this project demonstrated my ability to work in a team setting to create a fully functional 3D game, blending programming, and 3D rendering to deliver an engaging user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
