<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Hugo Academic CV Theme</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
      <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Hugo Academic CV Theme</description>
    <generator>Hugo Blox Builder (https://hugoblox.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>http://localhost:1313/media/icon_hu7729264130191091259.png</url>
      <title>Hugo Academic CV Theme</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Research Internship at the University of Utah</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/event/utah/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Aug 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/event/utah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;introduction&#34;&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This past summer, I had the incredible opportunity to work as an Undergraduate Research Assistant at the University of Utah&amp;rsquo;s School of Computing, in the Utah Artificial Intelligence and Robotics in Medicine (ARM) Lab led by Dr. Alan Kuntz. For three months, I dove deep into the world of medical robotics, focusing on advancing techniques in tendon-driven robotic systems. This experience not only honed my technical skills but also allowed me to collaborate with a brilliant team of researchers. My experience at the University of Utah was both academically challenging and immensely rewarding, helping me grow as a researcher and as a professional.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;predicting-tendon-robot-shape&#34;&gt;Predicting Tendon Robot Shape&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;video controls&gt;
  &lt;source src=&#34;IMG_4543.mp4&#34; type=&#34;video/mp4&#34;&gt;
  Your browser does not support the video tag.
&lt;/video&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The data collection process of the tendon robot shown above&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the main projects I tackled was developing a model to predict the shape of a tendon-driven robot. Under the leadership of Dr. Kuntz, the lab has been exploring these robots, which are fascinating because their shapes can be manipulated by adjusting tendon displacements, which are 4 strings wrapped around the tendon robot with different strengths, functioning much like muscles in a human body, pulling and shifting to create movement. However, accurately predicting these shapes, especially in a 3D space, is a complex problem that is ongoing at the time.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;During my internship, I was tasked with developing a machine learning model that could accurately predict the shape of the robot based on tendon displacement data. The problem had been partially addressed using other techniques, but we needed a more robust and efficient solution, especially for real-time applications.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To address this challenge, I employed Long Short-Term Memory (LSTM) networks — a type of recurrent neural network that excels at understanding sequences. My goal was to create a model that could predict the robot&amp;rsquo;s shape as 3D point clouds based on the current tendon displacements. After rigorous testing and iteration, the model exceeded the previous learning-based techniques by 11% in terms of Chamfer distance, a metric used to measure the similarity between point clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-deep-decoder-network-left-the-previous-method-compared-to-lstm-right-where-lstm-slightly-performs-better-than-the-previous-method&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Tendon LSTM&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /event/utah/comparison_hu917842899688811841.webp 400w,
               /event/utah/comparison_hu8307154731905453764.webp 760w,
               /event/utah/comparison_hu5340713185528468542.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/event/utah/comparison_hu917842899688811841.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;380&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Deep Decoder Network (Left), the previous method, compared to LSTM (Right), where LSTM slightly performs better than the previous method
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;collaborating-on-bayesian-optimization-for-surgical-retraction&#34;&gt;Collaborating on Bayesian Optimization for Surgical Retraction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Another exciting aspect of my internship was collaborating on a project that aimed to automate surgical retraction—a critical task in many medical procedures. Surgical retraction involves the use of tools to hold back tissue, providing the surgeon with better access to the area being operated on. Traditionally, this task requires manual input from surgical assistants, which can be imprecise and prone to human error. Our project sought to automate this process, using machine learning to optimize the positioning and force exerted by robotic retractors.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-da-vinci-research-kit-dvrk-robot&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;dVRK&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /event/utah/IMG_4532_hu11805555114194642311.webp 400w,
               /event/utah/IMG_4532_hu5292041122987521890.webp 760w,
               /event/utah/IMG_4532_hu15844732008137090232.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/event/utah/IMG_4532_hu11805555114194642311.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      da Vinci Research Kit (dVRK) robot
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The team I worked with adopted a Bayesian optimization approach to solve the problem, which is a powerful technique for finding the optimal set of parameters for a given system, particularly when the search space is large and complex. My role involved implementing different acquisition functions, which are used to determine the next point to sample in the optimization process. This approach led to significant improvements in detecting optimal attachment points for surgical tools, bringing us closer to fully automated surgical procedures.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-experiment-of-the-surgical-retraction-on-the-dvrk-simulation&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Simulation&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /event/utah/IMG_4295_hu3169504240056339831.webp 400w,
               /event/utah/IMG_4295_hu11116915037186733147.webp 760w,
               /event/utah/IMG_4295_hu6575657591454957371.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/event/utah/IMG_4295_hu3169504240056339831.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;284&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Experiment of the surgical retraction on the dVRK simulation
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By integrating various acquisition functions, we were able to find the function that improved the robot positioning and movement, allowing greater precision in revealing hidden areas of tissues more clearly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;reflections&#34;&gt;Reflections&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reflecting on my time in Dr. Kuntz lab, I can confidently say that this internship was one of the most formative experiences of my academic career. I was fortunate enough to work with a group of talented researchers who constantly challenged me to push my boundaries and think critically about the problems we were tackling.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The work we accomplished—developing predictive models for tendon-driven robots and automating surgical retraction—has the potential to make a real difference in the field of medical robotics. While there is still much more work to be done, I’m proud of the contributions I made and excited about the future of this research. I left the internship with a renewed passion for robotics and machine learning, and a deeper understanding of how these fields intersect in the context of healthcare.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, my summer at the University of Utah, under the mentorship of Dr. Alan Kuntz, was an unforgettable experience that has shaped my approach to research and problem-solving. I am incredibly grateful for the opportunity to contribute to such impactful projects and to work alongside some of the brightest minds in the field. As I continue my academic journey, I look forward to building on the skills and knowledge I gained during this internship, and I am excited to see where this research leads in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Group photo&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /event/utah/group_photo_hu14613843222847494310.webp 400w,
               /event/utah/group_photo_hu11429587030215895274.webp 760w,
               /event/utah/group_photo_hu13597567078321673485.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/event/utah/group_photo_hu14613843222847494310.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;570&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workspace Manager</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/workspace-manager/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Nov 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/workspace-manager/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this project, I worked with a team to develop Workspace Manager, a tool designed to streamline workflow by allowing users to create and manage custom workspaces. The goal of the application was to help users quickly launch all the necessary applications, files, and tools for specific tasks with just one click. This project was built using JavaScript and MongoDB as the backend database.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My contributions involved implementing the core functionality that allows users to save multiple file paths and applications into a workspace, making it easy to launch them simultaneously. I also worked on user authentication, incorporating encrypted passwords for secure account management and enabling multiple users to create their personalized workspaces.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This project gave me hands-on experience with database management in MongoDB, allowing us to store user preferences and workspace configurations. I also improved my ability to troubleshoot issues and collaborate effectively with a team under tight deadlines. The next steps for the project involve bug fixes and potential integration of Git automation to make workspace management even more seamless.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, Workspace Manager showcases my skills in developing practical tools that enhance user productivity, with a focus on user-friendly design and efficient back-end development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  id=&#34;figure-workspace-manager&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;Workspace Manager&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /projects/workspace-manager/image_hu14899443099680293474.webp 400w,
               /projects/workspace-manager/image_hu17588487741077846985.webp 760w,
               /projects/workspace-manager/image_hu3181325103095078584.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/workspace-manager/image_hu14899443099680293474.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;397&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;figcaption&gt;
      Workspace Manager
    &lt;/figcaption&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Experience</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/experience/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/experience/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Impact of attendance on SAT scores</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/sat-analysis/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/sat-analysis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Our mission is to increase student SAT scores by looking at factors like attendance and what section students focus on when studying for their SATs. We use two datasets in our analysis: The first one includes the mean SAT scores by section of each school in New York (2010); The second one is the enrollment and attendance history of the schools in New York. Our questions of interest include the following:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Does school attendance have an impact on the total SAT mean score?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Is there any difference in mean SAT Reading and Writing scores?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Through regression analysis and hypothesis testing we will provide statistical insight into these questions. We believe that students SAT scores would benefit from increasing their attendance in school as well as the knowledge that reading and writing are potentially linked thus improving one may have a doubling effect in overall score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;















&lt;figure  &gt;
  &lt;div class=&#34;flex justify-center	&#34;&gt;
    &lt;div class=&#34;w-100&#34; &gt;&lt;img alt=&#34;SAT analysis&#34; srcset=&#34;
               /projects/sat-analysis/image2_hu14842124428469607577.webp 400w,
               /projects/sat-analysis/image2_hu1901449112810700335.webp 760w,
               /projects/sat-analysis/image2_hu1565937759577204184.webp 1200w&#34;
               src=&#34;http://localhost:1313/projects/sat-analysis/image2_hu14842124428469607577.webp&#34;
               width=&#34;760&#34;
               height=&#34;543&#34;
               loading=&#34;lazy&#34; data-zoomable /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
  &lt;/div&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Check out our report 
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Highway crossing</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/projects/highway-crossing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/projects/highway-crossing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this collaborative project, I worked with a team of three to design and develop a 3D car highway crossing game using C# and OpenGL. The primary objective of the game was to guide a car through multiple lanes of fast-moving highway traffic without crashing into obstacles. The game offered players a challenging and engaging experience with progressively more difficult levels as they navigated through increasingly congested highways and obstacle speed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My key responsibilities included rendering 3D objects and textures using OpenGL, ensuring smooth visual transitions and enhancing the overall appearance of the game world. We utilized OpenGL to model cars, roads, and other environmental elements, focusing on clear and functional visuals rather than realistic graphics. Additionally, I implemented audio effects to provide a more immersive experience for players, with sounds for engine revs, collisions, and background ambiance.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Throughout development, we collaborated closely, solving challenges such as optimizing object collisions, creating responsive controls, and synchronizing audio with gameplay. The project not only deepened my understanding of OpenGL and C#, but also honed my skills in teamwork, problem-solving, and game mechanics development.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Overall, this project demonstrated my ability to work in a team setting to create a fully functional 3D game, blending programming, 3D rendering, and audio design to deliver an engaging user experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
